Previously on "Arrow"...
Maybe I'm finally ready
to admit that I still have
feelings for you, too.
No! Malcolm is planning
to level the Glades!
My father, he told me
that he failed the city,
but I never knew
what he meant until now.
Merlyn's plan is what I returned
from the island to stop.
Subtitles downloaded from www.OpenSubtitles.org
Oh, no!
You can survive this.
Make it home.
Make it better.
Right my wrongs.
Dad?!
Survive.
No! No!
I hope I didn't hurt you.
At least I can properly thank you
now for saving my life.
If I only knew
how you were
spending your nights...
My hope is that I can
explain everything to you
to help you understand.
You murdered my father!
You sentenced me
to that island,
to five years of hell.
I am truly sorry
for what happened to you.
You know I have
lost people.
Yeah, your wife.
Do you really think
that you're honoring
Tommy's mother
by destroying
the Glades?
As surely as you believe
you're honoring your father
with this hood.
Not a day goes by
I don't miss your father.
You'll see him soon.
You can't beat me, Oliver.
Yes, you're younger.
You're faster,
but you always seem
to come up short against me.
Want to know why?
Because you don't know,
in your heart,
what you're fighting for.
What you're willing
to sacrifice, and I do.
No one can stop
what's about to come.
Not even the Vigilante.
The plane's holding steady
at 33,000 feet.
That's the range
for missile intercept, sir.
Lock missile one
on target.
Missile one locked
on the jet's heat trail.
Prepare to launch
on my mark.
Yes, sir.
Fire! Fire the missile now!
I take back every joke
I made about you sticking
a tracking device in your boot.
♪ Arrow 1x23 ♪
Sacrifice
Original Air Date on May 15, 2013
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
Felicity's
at Queen Consolidated.
She's still going through the data
she pulled off Merlyn's network.
Did she find
anything?
Yeah, the design
schematics
of the earthquake
generator.
So we can shut it down.
Assuming
we find it in time.
Yeah, Felicity,
I got him.
Thank God.
Is he ok?
Mostly.
Ok.
I'm on my way.
Miss Smoak.
Where are you off to
in such a hurry?
Please.
Take a seat.
You know, I think
I'd rather stand.
You're not exactly
a hardened criminal, are you?
No, I'm not
any kind of criminal.
What do you call
computer hacking?
A hobby?
That I do not engage in.
Hey, I got a whole mess
of computer gobbedly gook
that I don't understand,
but it says otherwise.
I had my tech guys
go through your computer
at Queen Consolidated.
You used it to hack into
blackhawk squad security
to research arrows shipped to
a company called Sagittarius
and to analyze a water
sample to tie back
to a Vertigo drug lab.
These are all cases
involving...The Hood.
Tell me, Felicity.
What am I thinking?
Saved by the bell.
Excuse me.
Hello, Detective.
It's funny
you should call.
I got your trusty sidekick sitting
right in front of me.
I don't have a sidekick.
When I need help,
I call you.
Malcolm Merlyn plans to level
the Glades with a manmade earthquake
using technology
from Unidac Industries.
What?
Now you're just
trying to have some fun with me.
I don't know what
Merlyn's timetable is,
so you need to evacuate
the Glades immediately.
Get as many people
to safety as you can.
Whatever you think
of me, Detective,
please...believe this.
Sounds like you have
bigger problems than me.
Don't leave town.
You know...
I used to think the Vigilante
was a criminal, too,
but it seems to me,
whoever he is,
he's willing to sacrifice
an awful lot
to help the people
of this city.
Kind of makes him
a hero...
Doesn't it?
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
Look who it is.
My best friend in life.
Hey, buddy.
I took your advice,
you know.
I went to Laurel's,
to fight for her.
So imagine my surprise
seeing you there,
kissing her.
I'm sorry.
No, you're not.
Something's happening,
and it involves your father.
Keep my father
out of this.
Our fathers.
They aren't the men
we thought they were.
They made a plan together...
to destroy the Glades.
Do you have any idea
what you sound like right now?
Your father's going to do it.
Because he thinks
it will avenge your mother's death.
Do not talk about
my mother!
The difference
between us, Tommy,
is that I didn't find out the truth
about my father
until it was too late.
But you've always known,
deep down,
you have always known
the man he is.
I wish you would have
died on that island.
We need to reprogram
the missile.
I don't know how to reprogram
a missile launcher!
I do.
Watch out!
Oliver, put the chip in.
Make it quick,
I got a comm stat meeting in five.
I don't want to be late for
my own funeral.
I've got it under
good authority
that Malcolm Merlyn
is planning on leveling the Glades
using some kind
of earthquake device
made by Unidac
Industries.
Who's your source
in all this?
The Vigilante.
He called me.
Has been
for the last few months,
he's been helpful
on some cases.
You asked for the task
force to catch him.
You swore to me you'd bring him in.
I know.
I swore to uphold the law,
because the law is steady,
the law is unchanging,
the law needed to be protected.
But what are laws, rules,
if they don't protect people?
Now listen, I know,
I'm throwing away my career
by telling you this,
but I am willing to sacrifice
catching this guy
if it means saving people's lives!
Please.
You're suspended.
Leave the gun and your badge
with the duty sergeant.
Lieutenant...
Suspension or incarceration.
You choose.
No more lies, Mom.
The Undertaking.
We need to stop it.
Everything I have ever
said or done
has been to protect you
and your sister.
What about all those
people in the Glades?
I'm not their mother.
I spoke to Malcolm.
You what?!
He could have killed you.
He killed your father.
No, he didn't.
After the "Gambit"
went down,
dad and I both made it
to the life raft.
And then we drifted,
for days.
In the end,
there wasn't enough
food and water
for both of us.
So he shot himself
in the head.
I don't want to hear this.
He sacrificed himself...
So that I could live.
Do you really think
that I could
go on living
knowing that
you sacrificed
thousands more
in my name?
Mom.
Please.
You have to help me
stop Malcolm.
We need to know
where the device is.
Malcolm.
How can I help you?
I see.
Yes, thank you
for calling.
What is it?
Malcolm's accelerated
his timetable.
The Undertaking is...
Is happening tonight.
Where you going?
Somebody in this family
needs to put an end to this.
Whatever the cost.
Hi.
Hey.
I woke up and you were gone.
I'm really sorry
about that.
Oliver, I'm trying
not to think
that our history's repeating;
That you're scared again.
No.
That's not it.
Then will you tell me what's
going on with you?
There are so many things
that I have wanted
to tell you
for so long.
I never told you what
happened to me on the island.
You didn't have to.
I can see that
it changed you.
That's the thing.
Laurel, it didn't.
Those five years
didn't change me.
They just...
They scraped away
all the things that I wasn't,
and revealed the person
I always was,
which is the person...
That's who you always saw.
I don't know how you saw it,
but you did.
Nobody in my life
is who I thought they were...
Except you.
Laurel, I need you
to do something for me.
Stay out of the Glades tonight.
Why?
You'll know soon.
One way or the other.
I have to go.
It's over.
Laurel and me, I mean.
She's with Oliver,
again. Always.
I'm sorry, Son.
Yeah, and he said
you wanted to nuke
the Glades or something.
You know,
it's funny,
scotch doesn't make it
any more believable.
Maybe after your jihad,
we can grab
some steaks.
It's true, Tommy.
It's the reason
I closed your mother's clinic.
I didn't want
to see it leveled.
What?
I have something
I'd like you to listen to.
The night
your mother died,
she called me.
I awoke to a voicemail
from her.
Dad...
Her final gift to me.
Malcolm,
I'm in trouble.
I told--I told him
to take everything.
My money...my ring.
Turn it off.
They shot me.
I screamed for help,
but no one would come.
No one would come.
Malcolm, I don't want
to die alone.
She bled out into the pavement
while people passed,
did nothing.
Your mother
built her clinic in the Glades
because she wanted
to save this city.
It can't be saved.
Because the people
there don't want it to be saved.
So you kill them all--
Yes!
They deserve to die!
All of them!
The way she died.
The Undertaking
is happening tonight.
Oliver, Felicity
may have found something.
This symbol is a map of the old
subway tunnel system.
That's what got us
thinking the Undertaking
is connected to the Glades.
What if it's more
specific than that?
What do you mean?
If I had a machine
that could trigger
an earthquake in an otherwise
geologically stable area,
where would I position it?
Underground.
Yeah.
This is a U.S.
geological survey
of the tectonic plates
running underneath Starling City.
This red line here
is a known fault
that runs right below
the Glades.
About a mile, the fault
runs underneath the old
Tenth Street subway line.
Dollars to donuts, the seismic
device is somewhere along there.
I know where it is.
Now is not a good time.
Yeah, understate much?
Mom has a whole bunch
of reporters here.
She's holding a press conference
or something.
What channel?
Ah, it looks like
all of them.
Felicity, pull up
the local news, please.
My name is
Moira Dearden Queen.
I am the acting CEO
of Queen Consolidated.
And God forgive me,
I have failed the city.
For the past five years,
under the threat for my life
and the lives of my family...
I have been complicit
in an undertaking
with one horrible purpose--
to destroy the Glades
and everyone in it.
I realize now
that my family's safety
will mean nothing
if I let this
dreadful act occur.
But you need to know
that the architect
of this nightmare...
is Malcolm Merlyn.
No!
Yes, and I have proof
that he has killed dozens
in pursuit of this madness.
Adam Hunt, Frank Chen,
and my husband...
Robert.
Please.
If you reside in the Glades,
you need to get out now.
Your lives and the lives
of your children depend on it.
Please.
I don't understand.
I'm sorry. I love you.
I love Roy.
Roy?
He lives
in the Glades.
I can't leave him there.
Sweetheart--Thea!
Moira Queen, you're under arrest
for conspiracy.
Anything you say can and will
be used against you in a court of law.
You have the right
to an attorney.
Is it true?
Did you kill
all those people?
I did what I had to do.
Freeze!
Malcolm Merlyn,
you are under arrest.
Dad, no!
Please, Dad.
Stay back.
I don't want to hurt you.
You can't.
And you can't stop me.
Oliver, I'm sorry.
Don't be.
She gave those
people a chance.
I thought Merlyn
broke your bow.
I have another.
I was going over
the device schematics.
The device can be set
for a timed detonation
or can be remote activated
by a mobile transmitter.
Something Merlyn
could have on him.
Listen, Oliver,
if we can just
get our hands
on this transmitter,
maybe we don't need
to track down the device.
It's too big
of an "if," Diggle.
I need you
in the subway.
Find the device,
disarm it.
So you can take on
Merlyn by yourself?
I have to.
Oh, he'll kill you, Oliver.
I know.
He's beaten me twice.
And I don't know
how to stop him.
Ok. Well, how about this time,
you bring along something
you didn't have the last time
you two fought--
Me.
I can't let you.
I can't let you do this
by yourself, man.
Oliver, you are not alone,
not since
you brought me into this.
Us into this.
Besides, army regulations--
a soldier never lets
a brother go into battle alone.
I'm out of bows.
I got my gun.
I guess it's up to me
to do the dismantling.
This whole area
is ground zero.
I want you
out of here.
If you're not leaving,
I'm not leaving.
Besides, if I don't
deactivate the device,
who will?
You were right.
I need one more
thing from you.
Yeah? What do I got
left to give?
I know where Merlyn
is keeping the device.
It's in an abandoned subway
station near Puckett Street.
How do you know?
That's where
his wife was murdered.
I need someone I can trust
to deactivate the device.
We have a mutual friend
that I think could...
Talk you through it.
She says you care
about the people of this city,
that it needs you.
Right now, Detective...
It needs you.
Earlier today, Moira Queen,
CEO of Queen Consolidated,
admitted to a conspiracy
to destroy the Glades.
Everyone within a five mile
radius is asked to evacuate.
Please leave the area
immediately.
Evacuation centers
have been set up in Starling City.
Looks like we missed him.
Shado!
Slade!
Boy, I should
have figured.
You couldn't
save the day...
without making a mess.
Where's Shado?
I thought
she was with you.
Actually...
She's with me.
Let her go!
It's over, Fyers!
Let her go.
Amazing.
A two year operation undone
because a young playboy happened
to wash up on the shore,
and now here you are--
a killer.
You wanted
nothing more than to leave this island,
and now you can.
I can call in a rescue ship,
you can go home.
Tell me, Mr. Queen.
Are you prepared
to sacrifice your freedom...
For her?
Guess so.
Tommy.
Tommy. Tommy!
Oliver.
Where's your father?
Ohh. I don't know.
You were right.
You were right about him.
Oliver.
Are you going to kill him?
Get to safety.
Looks like a false wall.
Welcome, gentlemen.
I've been waiting for you.
I wanted to see you
watch your city die.
Where's
the transmitter?
Somewhere I can
easily get to it.
I doubt it.
You'll be too dead.
Aaah!
Stairs. Go, go.
So tell me--
are you ready to die?
You found it yet, Detective?
Not exactly sure
what I'm looking for.
Do you want me
to describe it to you?
No, I've got it.
You should see something
that looks like a circuit board.
Pull it out.
Do you see a timer?
Seven minutes.
Ok. Well, the good news is,
this is going to be
a paperweight in three.
What do you got there, grandpa?
Hey! Hey!
Hey!
Back off!
Learn how to count, jerkwad.
There's three of us.
Oh, is that right?
'Cause I only count one.
With a gun.
Where did you learn
how to do that?
I guess I have wicked aim.
What?
I went to your house.
Yeah, I figured I'd run for my life
with everyone else.
Did you--did you
come to rescue me?
Yeah.
Come on.
There are three wires--
you need a green one,
a yellow and one blue.
Cut the blue.
All right,
I got it, I got it.
Oh, my God.
No, no, no, no, no!
There must be some sort
of anti-tamper safeguard.
Hold on. I'm going to try to
figure out how to override it.
Not enough time.
There's not enough time!
Just hold on!
Not enough time.
Laurel.
Dad, don't worry,
I got your message,
and I did not
come into work today.
Save it, kiddo,
we both know you're there.
But listen--you got to
get out of the Glades.
You got to get out of
the Glades right now! Ok, please.
Dad?
Right now, Laurel!
Daddy,
you're scaring me.
Sorry, but I'm not...
I'm not going
to make it.
What?
What?!
You have to promise me
one thing, Laurel.
You're not going
to die along with me.
You have to go on
with your life.
After your sister died,
I pushed people away,
I became like a ghost.
I didn't think I had
the right to live
when my baby girl
didn't.
Promise me
you're not going
to make the same
mistakes as I did.
Where are you?
Promise me, Laurel.
Promise me.
I promise.
I love you, honey,
now and forever.
I love you.
Dad!
Detective Lance?
I need you to listen to me
very carefully.
You do know how dangerous
it is to text and drive,
right? It can wait!
No, it can't. I'm trying to find us
another route out of here.
Let me. It's not
worth the risk.
Roy!
Help me out! Help me out!
Help me out!
Roy, stop! Roy!
The device is about
to go off any second!
I can't leave
anyone behind.
I know you think
you have something to prove.
But you're not the Vigilante!
I can't do this
unless I know you're safe.
Then you better
haul ass out of it.
Don't struggle.
It's over.
There was never any
doubt in the outcome.
Don't worry. Your mother
and sister will be joining you in death.
Survive.
Thank you
for teaching me
what I'm fighting for.
But my father taught me how.
Come on!
Oliver,
Lance did it.
It's over.
If I've learned anything
as a successful businessman,
it's...
Redundancy.
Felicity...
there's another device.
There's two of them!
What the hell's
happening?!
Ok, that's enough.
Ohh!
I turned
the damn thing off!
Merlyn had a second device!
My daughter! Laurel!
She's at CNRI!
Run!
Laurel!
Oliver?
Are you ok?
Yeah.
The damage seems
to be contained
on the east side,
past Wells Street.
Laurel.
Are you going
to be ok?
Go, go, go.
Help!
Please! Help me!
Tommy!
What are you doing here?
I kind of figured that you might
come back to CNRI.
You came here for me?
I love you.
Get up! Go!
I'm right behind you!
Laurel! Laurel!
Dad! Dad!
Oh, thank God.
No!
No! Laurel!
No, you can't!
Tommy!
You can't!
It's too late,
it's too late.
Tommy!
Ah, Tommy.
You're going to be fine.
Another thing...
We got to disagree on.
Tommy...
Is--is Laurel safe?
Is Laurel safe?
I tried to get her out of here.
Yeah, yeah, you did.
You saved her.
I'm going to get you
out of here.
You're going to be fine.
Stop.
I'm sorry.
No. Don't apologize.
I was angry.
And I was jealous. I--
I am my father.
No.
No, you're not.
Did--did you kill him?
No.
Thank you.
No, no!
Tommy!
It should have been me.
Open your eyes, Tommy!
Open your eyes.
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
Best watched using Open Subtitles MKV Player