Previously on "Battlestar Galactica":
l was burnt out.
l started taking... stims.
- What are these?
- Stims.
And by the look of it,
she's been taking them by the handful.
Coming in late cos you're hungover is
bad, but when you back out on a mission?
Unlike you,
l don't take a bunch of pills...
and then climb in my cockpit so wired
that l can't land the frakking ship.
Starbuck, you're an embarrassment.
l need you back in the CIC.
It just ain't the same without you in there...
intimidating the inmates.
No, no.
There are 12 Cylon models. But in the
occupation on New Caprica, l saw seven.
- Who are the final five?
- l can't talk about that.
(Baltar) What is it talking about?
(Number Six) Most Cylons think
the mind of the hybrid has gone mad...
and the vocalisations are meaningless.
But not everyone thinks that.
You'll delete the order from your logs.
Execute.
(gunshot)...
(gasps)
It's OK. It's OK.
There is something beautiful...
miraculous,
between life and death.
There's no food to be salvaged?
What about the good food we had stored...
before we started
churning out the contaminated stuff?
The newly processed bad food...
went into the depleted storage system.
Everything's tainted.
(Cottle) Sharon's finding algae
for us to process.
It's tough to choke down,
but it's almost pure protein.
What if Sharon comes back and reports
there is no clear passage to this planet?
Then the question is, Doc,
how long can we survive?
With the rations we've been on?
l'd say seven to ten days.
- (Roslin) When is she due back?
- She was due three hours ago.
The, uh, radiation levels are high,
but she's strong and...
she's, uh...
She'll be here any moment.
- No, l'm sorry. l don't have anything.
- To share.
l told you, Starbuck, l don't have anything.
Get off my back.
- l saw a protein bar.
- l gave it to Cottle.
Right. Right after l gave him head.
- Now l'm a liar?!
- If the shoe fits...
All right, can it!
Kat, get down here.
All right. For frak's sake, everybody eat.
We're getting paranoid over this hunger.
(Kat) Here, baby. Eat this.
(Starbuck) Oh, my gods, that's good.
(alarm)...
(Baltar) Somewhere to be, D'Anna?
(Number Three) Ssh. You'll wake Caprica.
l'd love to hang around with you two
all day, but... l got things to do.
l'll never understand
what you all do all day long,
living on this thing like fleas on a cat.
Where do you suppose
she takes herself off to, then?
- You're not the only one asking that.
- l'm not?
What do you mean?
- She's been doing things.
- "Doing things"?
What things?
(loud hissing)...
(talking drowned out by noise)...
(man) Go ahead,
l've got your helmet.
- There you go. Got you.
- (man #2) Easy.
(man) Prepare the starboard side
for wash down.
- All the way down to fifth.
- (man #2) Right through here, Lieutenant.
Radiation negative.
There's a way through the star cluster.
And l found the planet,
on the other side.
l skimmed it, l took photos.
There's huge swaths of algae,
just like we thought.
- It's black.
- (Apollo) She's a Cylon.
She can handle a radiation dose that big.
- We think. Someone call Cottle!
- l'm fine.
Maybe you are, but...
a human might not be able to make it.
So then how do we get tens of thousands
of humans through there?
(Sharon) So we can make it through
in two jumps with a stop right there.
- There's no solution with a single jump?
- The cluster's too big.
It's too big to go around, too.
Civvy ships aren't shielded enough
to jump in the middle of that radiation.
l would say 80% of the people
on board would die.
- Can we send Galactica for food?
- And put it where?
- What?
- It'd take dozens of trips.
Each time we'd leave the fleet vulnerable.
We can't bring the food to the people.
What if we bring the people to the food,
put the people on Galactica?
Send the civilian ships with skeleton crew,
give them radiation meds.
Except that the radiation
would fry the civvy ships' nav systems.
They wouldn't be able to see squat. There
wouldn't be a way to calculate a jump out.
It's worse than that. Once you jump in,
the light is so blinding you begin to drift,
and before you can get your bearings...
you're over there.
(Apollo) No visual contact.
Instruments blinded by radiation.
They'd get lost, they'd burn up.
Pilot ship.
We pair a Raptor with each civilian ship.
Raptor navigation systems are hardened.
They could handle the radiation.
Each Raptor leads a civilian ship
through the cluster,
then they both jump out together.
The question is...
how many jumps will it take?
Five round trips.
You heard. Five round trips.
On our outbound jumps,
we'll each be responsible...
for relaying jump coordinates
to our own specific civilian ship,
nailing them to jump points
and ensuring they don't drift off.
Sir, will we get fed when we get there?
Eventually, yes, but only after
we find the algae and get it processed.
Oh!
But the truth is, nausea from radiation
exposure will take care of our appetites.
You'll all be issued with
radiation badges to track our exposure.
White, like this, you're OK.
As your exposure increases, it'll darken.
If it approaches this,
you'll be pulled from duty.
Keep checking your badges.
It's every pilot's own responsibility...
to monitor their own badge.
Starbuck.
Remember, we're all flying solo
on this mission.
So there'll be nobody
to bitch slap you if you get tired...
or start seeing toasters on your wing.
We'll be issuing stims, so use them.
Are you crazy?
We can't use stims.
- Problem?
- Stims amp up your metabolism.
We've got nothing to burn.
We'll be flying into the sides of the ships.
- They'd mess us up?
- You used to like stims, Kat.
Personal discretion on the stims.
We're taking the first load of civilians
on board as we speak.
That's it.
Skids up in four hours.
(Dualla) There is no food here. There are
no rations anywhere on this ship.
If someone told you there was food,
they were lying!
If you leave this area,
force will be used.
Once we get through the star cluster, you
will be returned to your designated ships.
Sacha!
(man) Keep following.
Down to the front.
My name isn't "Sacha".
My name is Captain Louanne Katraine,
you understand me?
Sacha and you were a lifetime ago.
Right, right.
Cos you got this now, right?
No more hanging with the sinners, huh?
Stay away from me.
Do you understand me?
Do they even know who you really are?
Fancy bumping into you here.
Can you believe l'm lost again?
l can never find my way around this place.
Where have you been?
l've been talking with Simon about our
move toward Earth. There's some debate.
Of course, if l spoke to the relevant Simon
he'd ascertain you were at this meeting?
Beg your pardon?
l hear that you've been
going off by yourself, "doing things".
Really?
Now, who would tell you
anything about my business?
- So it's true?
- Caprica?
Did you know you have
some dried goo in your hair?
That can happen when you resurrect.
Now l understand what you've been
doing with yourself all these afternoons.
Do you have any idea
what you are accusing me of?
Yes...
Intentionally killing yourself over and over
so you can download over and over.
But death's just a revolving door, isn't it?
Come here!
Ooh!
What do you want?!
Take it down a notch, baby. Relax.
l'm not looking for a business partner.
l told you to stay the frak away from me.
Yeah, cos if they find out who you are,
they'll kick you out the service, or worse.
Now, do you think l want that?
l don't want that,
cos if that happens...
who's gonna feed me? (sniggers)
Oh, come on,
you're getting three squares.
We don't.
And l don't have anything stashed, Enzo.
Yeah, sure you don't.
Oh, we go back, baby.
Since when is it a crime to...
take care of your own? Hm?
Remember, l know who you are,
and l know how to make you happy.
Get your hands off of me.
Colonel.
Go ahead.
- (man) Welcome back, sir.
- (woman) Good to see you, sir.
(man #2) Colonel's back on board.
- (man #3) Welcome, sir.
- (man #4) It's good to see you, sir.
- (man #5) We're with you, sir.
- (man #6) Welcome back.
Enough!
Don't you people have jobs to do?
- Welcome back, Colonel.
- Admiral.
Apollo, Galactica.
Launch Raptors on your orders.
(Apollo) Shepherds, find your sheep.
Stay close. Never let them go.
These crews are counting on us.
- Apollo, Starbuck on station.
- (Kat) l got visual on "Chiron".
(Apollo) Hotdog.
"Adriatic" in sight. OK.
When you jump in,
you'll be disoriented.
Take it one step at a time.
Find your sheep, work the jump
calculations and get them out.
Remember, we do not stay
beyond our radiation-dose limit.
(Hoshi) Apollo reports pilots in position, sir.
Initiate jump on his command.
Galactica will follow.
(man) Aye aye, sir.
Raptors, Apollo.
We jump on my mark.
- Three, two...
- Jumping...
...one. Mark.
Whoa!
What is this?
l can't see anything.
Frak!
Oh!
Ah! Got you!
- Kat, you got yours?
- Affirmative, Apollo.
Only got eyes for the Chiron.
Relaying coordinates.
Squadron, Apollo.
l have Thera Sita.
Relaying jump coordinates
to her right now.
Apollo, Starbuck. l got mine.
Frak. l'm just barely holding on here.
l lost mine! Has anyone seen Adriatic?
She has lost her jump coordinates.
(Helo) Hotdog, negative!
Negative on Adriatic.
Hotdog, ease off on the control, man!
Ease up with the stick.
It's a Raptor.
Frak it, frak it!
Apollo, it's Galactica actual.
You've reached your radiation-dose limit.
You've got to jump.
- Count us down.
- (Apollo) Roger that.
No! Hold on!
Apollo, please wait.
Hotdog, listen!
We have to get out of here!
l can find them!
l can find them! Hold on!
- Please wait!
- (Apollo) Jump on my mark!
- Please, wait!
- (Apollo) One, two...
- No! Please! Wait!
- Mark!
(Hotdog) We can't leave without them!
Frak! Frak!
Jump complete.
DRADIS is back online.
Ship reports moderate hull damage.
"Galactica", Apollo.
First trip complete.
Raptors, land your birds
and prepare to jump back...
for the second group of civilians.
We lost the Adriatic.
- It's only our first jump.
- Yes, it is.
(alarm)
Carina, Kat!
Report your location!
Kat, Apollo.
Do you have the Carina?
Negative!
Radiation's pissing on my nav.
l can't see jack!
OK. l found her.
- No! Frak!
- (Apollo) Kat! Kat, report!
Godsdammit!
(Apollo) All right, Kat!
Time's up. We're jumping on my mark!
- Three, two, one... Mark!
- Godsdammit! The Carina!
l lost...
l lost her.
(Apollo) All right. We managed
to get another eight ships through,
but we still lost one.
We gotta get better at tracking our sheep.
Quicker reaction times out of the jumps.
Racetrack, don't be calling out
coordinates to the wrong ship.
l got mixed up.
Keep checking your instruments,
and recheck them.
The instruments are crap.
All right.
That concludes Outbound Four.
This is Return Four.
One to go.
All right, get some rest.
Come on.
Here's the report from the doc.
A hundred marines too weak to work.
Two hundred more are ready to drop.
That's gonna slow down the harvest.
Last batch of passengers
kicked up some trouble.
You... you get these people
to the other side...
and they think there's a diner and a chef
waiting to take their order.
l know.
When they gonna learn they gotta
process the thing first, for frak's sake?
Try telling that
to a bunch of empty stomachs.
l hear they're still eating paper.
Is that true?
No... Paper shortage.
Not a good sign.
No, sir.
So, while you resurrect
do you see the faces of the final five?
The ones that no one's seen.
What do you want to know about them?
l could be a Cylon.
l would stop being a traitor
to one set of people...
and be a hero to another.
l'd have a place to belong.
You would help me understand my destiny.
- Have you seen my face?
- Your face?
Yes, my face.
Can't remember.
l've been trying to get it all down on paper
while it's still fresh in my mind,
but nothing much comes out.
It's rubbish. l can't remember.
Cylons, humans...
We're all just trying to discover...
who we are.
Aren't we?
Hey, Enzo.
Yeah.
l took the name Louanne Katraine
from a girl who died...
two days before the attack on Caprica.
It got me through the background checks.
Yeah, times were rough.
Keep going.
l was a drug runner.
Enzo was my supplier.
What do you want? We were truckers,
OK? We just moved stuff.
People?
You see, some think that that's the way
that the Cylons infiltrated Caprica.
They seeded themselves in the colonies,
then used criminals...
to get them into the capital.
Anyone who's found guilty of helping
the Cylons is considered a traitor.
- We didn't carry Cylons.
- How do you know?
- Cos nobody knew they looked like us.
- Then how do you know you didn't?!
- How do you know?
- You think l'm a traitor?
You think l'm a traitor?
No.
l don't think you're a traitor.
You're a "smart young woman".
That's what the old man said.
You're just not smart enough
to accept who you are.
You see, you lied your way
into the company of good people.
Starbuck, don't tell the admiral.
Please... Please don't, or I...
Or what?
Starbuck, please.
Just let me tell him myself.
Please just let me.
Can you do that?
Gods.
(sobs)...
(Hybrid) One degree...
Angle nominal...
Seascape portrait of
the woman-child cavern of the soul...
Under pressure-heat ratio...
Lines of evolution have buried their fuse...
So this is where you got the idea
to start intentionally downloading.
Gestalt therapy and escape clauses...
Right, let's see what we can find out.
(Hybrid) Throughout history,
the nexus between man and machine...
has spun some of
the most dramatic, compelling...
Gaius...
what do you think you're doing?
Don't touch it!
Intelligence.
A mind that burns like a fire.
Yes. l'm here.
Find the hand that lies
in the shadow of the light.
In the eye of the husband
of the eye of the cow.
Are you all right?
It just speaks nonsense,
doesn't it?
l don't think anything it says is nonsense.
"The husband of the eye."
"The eye of the..."
Hera.
Hera is sometimes referred to
as "cow-eyed Hera".
- And the husband of Hera...
- Is Jupiter.
The Eye of Jupiter.
That's written about in the ancient texts.
Oh, gods.
Could there be a connection
between their gods and ours?
What does it mean?
It's a location.
A planet hidden in the shadow of light -
probably a cluster of stars.
That will lead us to the Eye of Jupiter.
And to the hand...
"hidden in the shadow of light".
It's probably some type of artefact.
A hand.
As in five.
Five faces.
Now all we have to do
is find the right planet...
the right star cluster.
Accept who you are.
Yeah.
Remember me?
Yeah, l remember you.
Thieving bastard.
You'll ruin everything l've got.
Come here.
Faru Sadin, report your location.
Kat! You got Faru Sadin?
Kat, have you got "Faru Sadin"? Kat?
Kat, report.
Negative.
Kat.
Frak! l've lost the Faru Sadin.
Sir. Escalating damage reports,
ship-wide.
Engineers are reporting
a cascade of pressure failures.
Jump spot's become unstable.
We gotta get out of here.
- Open line.
- (Hoshi) Aye, sir.
Channel open.
Apollo, Galactica actual.
Jump all.
Repeat, jump all.
All right, admiral's calling it.
Everyone, jump on my mark.
- l'm not losing another one.
- Three, two, one... Mark!
Apollo, Starbuck.
l don't see Kat.
Report.
We're missing Faru Sadin and one Raptor.
It's Kat. She must have missed the order.
She's still out there.
Damn.
Faru Sadin, this is Kat.
Report your location.
Frak!
(Tigh) Come on, kid.
Come on home.
(Hoshi) It's them!
She brought 'em home!
Galactica, Kat.
Mission accomplished.
- They said you wanted to see me.
- (weakly) Yeah.
l don't think we should end
the way we ended.
Listen, um...
everybody is...
Everybody is stuck...
with the things that they're not proud of.
And that, uh...
that thing about "good people", I, uh...
l didn't mean that.
Yeah, l know.
Here.
Take these. Sleeping pills.
Enough.
So, uh... take them if you want.
Thank you.
l got to go.
Admiral, I...
l know. l'm... l'm sorry.
l'm not here to lecture.
l'm letting you know about a promotion.
l'm making you CAG again.
Sir, you know
l'm not getting out of here, right?
But you earned it.
What you did
was harder than facing a bullet,
and you did it without
putting one other soul in harm's way.
l don't know if l could've done that.
l wish there was
something more l could give.
No.
It's good.
l would like to be CAG very much.
Thank you.
Listen... There's a...
There's a thing...
a reason why
you might not want to do this.
Kara knows what it is...
but l wanted to tell you myself.
l don't need to know anything
other than what l already know.
When you were CAG,
you protected your people,
made them feel safe enough to be brave.
What you were gonna say
doesn't change that.
Are you... staying?
Oh, l'm staying.
l love this sickbay, in a way.
It reminds me of
where my son Zak was born.
Carolanne was so happy.
She was convinced,
both times,
that she was having a girl.
So it was a surprise at the end.
Did you want a girl, too?
Yeah.
Three's a good round number.
l need your verdict on this one.
What if?
- l hate it.
- Ah.