Subtitles downloaded from www.OpenSubtitles.org
(BOY COUGHlNG)
(TAKE ME OUT TO THE BALL GAME
PLAYlNG ON VlDEO GAME)
(ELECTRONIC BEEPING)
Hi, honey.
Hi, Mom.
You feeling any better?
A little bit.
Guess what?
What?
Your grandfather's here.
Mom, can't you tell him
l'm sick?
You're sick?
That's why he's here.
He'll pinch my cheek.
l hate that.
Maybe he won't.
Hey, how is the sickie? Huh?
l think l'll leave
you two pals alone.
l brought you
a special present.
What is it?
Open it up.
A book?
That's right.
When l was your age,
television was called books.
And this is
a special book.
lt was the book
my father used to read to me
when l was sick,
and l used to read it
to your father.
And today,
l'm gonna read it to you.
Has it got
any sports in it?
Are you kidding?
Fencing, fighting,
torture, revenge,
giants, monsters,
chases, escapes,
true love, miracles.
Doesn't sound too bad.
l'll try and stay awake.
Well, thank you very much.
Very nice of you.
Your vote of confidence
is overwhelming.
All right.
"The Princess Bride,
"by S. Morgenstern.
"Chapter one.
"Buttercup was raised
on a small farm
in the country of Florin.
"Her favorite pastimes
were riding her horse
"and tormenting the farm boy
that worked there.
"His name was Westley,
but she never
called him that."
Isn't that
a wonderful beginning?
GRANDSON:
Yeah, it's really good.
"Nothing gave Buttercup
as much pleasure
as ordering Westley around."
Farm Boy,
polish my horse's saddle.
l want to see my face
shining in it by morning.
As you wish.
GRANDFATHER: "'As you wish'
was all he ever said to her."
Farm Boy,
fill these with water.
Please?
As you wish.
"That day,
she was amazed to discover
"that when he was saying,
'As you wish,'
"what he meant was,
'I love you.'
"And even more amazing
was the day she realized
she truly loved him back."
Farm Boy,
fetch me that pitcher.
As you wish.
GRANDSON: Hold it. Hold it.
What is this?
Are you trying to trick me?
Where's the sports?
ls this a kissing book?
Wait. Just wait.
When does it get good?
Keep your shirt on.
Let me read.
"Westley had no money
for marriage,
"so he packed
his few belongings
and left the farm
"to seek his fortune
across the sea.
"It was a very emotional time
for Buttercup."
GRANDSON:
I don't believe this.
l fear l'll never
see you again.
Of course you will.
But what if something
happens to you?
Hear this now.
l will always come for you.
But how can you be sure?
This is true love.
Do you think this happens
every day?
GRANDFATHER:
"Westley didn't reach
his destination.
"His ship was attacked
by the Dread Pirate Roberts,
"who never
left captives alive.
"When Buttercup got the news
that Westley was murdered..."
GRANDSON:
Murdered by pirates is good.
"...she went into her room
and shut the door.
"And for days,
she neither slept nor ate."
l will never love again.
(SHEEP BLEATlNG)
"Five years later,
the main square of Florin City
was filled as never before
"to hear the announcement
of the great Prince
Humperdinck's bride-to-be."
My people,
a month from now,
our country will have
its 500th anniversary.
On that sundown,
l shall marry a lady
who was once
a commoner like yourselves.
But perhaps
you will not find her common
now.
Would you like to meet her?
ALL: Yes!
My people,
the Princess Buttercup!
(BUGLES PLAYlNG)
GRANDFATHER:
"Buttercup's emptiness
consumed her.
"Although the law of the land
gave Humperdinck the right
"to choose his bride,
"she did not love him.
(BlRDS CHlRPlNG)
"Despite Humperdinck's
reassurance that she would
grow to love him,
"the only joy she found
was in her daily ride."
(NElGHlNG)
MAN: A word, my lady?
We are but poor,
lost circus performers.
ls there a village nearby?
There is nothing nearby,
not for miles.
Then there will be no one
to hear you scream.
(GASPS)
What is that
you're ripping?
lt is fabric from the uniform
of an army officer of Guilder.
Who is Guilder?
The country across the sea.
The sworn enemy of Florin.
Go! Once the horse
reaches the castle,
the fabric will make
the prince suspect
the Guilderians
have abducted his love.
When he finds her body dead
on the Guilder frontier,
his suspicions will be
totally confirmed.
You never said anything
about killing anyone.
l've hired you
to help me start a war.
lt's a prestigious
line of work
with a long
and glorious tradition.
l just don't think it's right
killing an innocent girl.
Am l going mad
or did the word "think"
escape your lips?
You were not hired
for your brains,
you hippopotamic landmass!
l agree with Fezzik.
The sot has spoken.
What happens to her is not
truly your concern.
l will kill her.
And remember this.
Never forget this!
When l found you,
you were so slobbering drunk
you couldn't buy brandy!
And you !
Friendless. Brainless.
Helpless! Hopeless!
Do you want me
to send you back
to where you were?
Unemployed? ln Greenland?
That Vizzini,
he can fuss.
Fuss. Fuss.
l think he like
to scream at us.
Probably he means no harm.
He's really very short
on charm.
You have
a great gift for rhyme.
Yes. Yes. Some other time.
VlZZlNl: Enough of that!
lNlGO: Fezzik,
are there rocks ahead?
FEZZlK: lf there are,
we'll all be dead.
VlZZlNl: No more rhymes now,
l mean it!
Anybody want a peanut?
(VlZZlNl GRUNTlNG)
We'll reach the cliffs
by dawn.
Why are you doing that?
Are you sure
nobody's follow us?
That would be inconceivable.
Despite what you think,
you will be caught.
And when you are,
the Prince will see
you all hanged.
Of all the necks
on this boat, Highness,
the one you should be
worrying about is your own.
Stop doing that!
We can all relax.
lt's almost over.
You are sure
nobody's follow us?
As l told you,
it would be absolutely,
totally and in all other ways
inconceivable.
No one in Guilder knows
what we've done
and no one in Florin
could have gotten here
so fast.
Out of curiosity,
why do you ask?
No reason.
Suddenly, l just happen
to look behind us
and something is there.
What?
Probably some local fisherman
out for a pleasure cruise
at night through
eel-infested waters.
(WATER SPLASHES)
What? Go in ! Get after her!
l don't swim.
l only dog paddle.
(GRUNTS)
Veer left!
Left! Left!
(SHRlEKlNG)
VlZZlNl: Do you know what
that sound is, Highness?
Those are
the shrieking eels!
lf you don't believe me,
just wait.
They always grow louder
when they're about to
feed on human flesh !
(GASPS)
lf you swim back now,
l promise no harm
will come to you.
l doubt you'll get
such an offer
from the eels.
(SHRlEKlNG)
(SCREAMlNG)
She doesn't get eaten
by the eels at this time.
What?
The eel doesn't get her.
l'm explaining to you
because you look nervous.
l wasn't nervous.
Maybe l was
a little bit concerned,
but that's not the same thing.
Because we can stop now
if you want.
No, you could read
a little bit more if you want.
"Do you know what
that sound is, Highness?
"Those are
the shrieking eels."
We're past that, Grandpa.
You read it already.
Oh. Oh, my goodness.
l did. l'm sorry.
l beg your pardon.
All right. All right.
Let's see,
she was in the water.
The eel was coming after her.
She was frightened.
The eel started to charge her,
and then...
Put her down.
Just put her down.
l think he's getting closer.
He's no concern of ours.
Sail on !
l suppose you think
you're brave, don't you?
Only compared to some.
lNlGO: Look!
He's right on top of us!
l wonder if he is using
the same wind we are using.
Whoever he is,
he's too late. See?
The Cliffs of lnsanity!
Hurry up! Move the thing !
And that other thing !
Move it!
We're safe. Only Fezzik
is strong enough
to go up our way.
He'll have to
sail around for hours
till he finds a harbor.
(BlRDS CAWlNG)
He's climbing the rope
and he's gaining on us.
lnconceivable.
Faster!
FEZZlK: l thought
l was going faster.
You were supposed
to be this colossus.
You were this great
legendary thing.
And yet, he gains!
Well,
l'm carrying three people,
and he got only himself.
l do not accept excuses.
l'm just going to have to
find myself a new giant,
that's all.
Don't say that, Vizzini.
Please?
Did l make it clear
that your job is at stake?
He's got very good arms.
He didn't fall?
lnconceivable.
You keep using that word.
l do not think it means
what you think it means.
lNlGO:
My God. He's climbing.
Whoever he is, he's obviously
seen us with the Princess
and must, therefore, die.
You, carry her.
We'll head straight
for the Guilder frontier.
Catch up when he's dead.
lf he falls, fine.
lf not, the sword.
l'm going to duel him
left-handed.
You know
what a hurry we're in !
lt's the only way
l can be satisfied.
lf l use my right,
over too quickly.
Oh, have it your way.
You be careful.
People in masks
cannot be trusted.
l'm waiting !
Hello there!
Slow going?
Look, l don't mean to be rude,
but this is not
as easy as it looks,
so l'd appreciate it
if you wouldn't distract me.
Sorry.
Thank you.
l don't suppose
you could speed things up?
lf you're in such a hurry,
you could lower a rope
or a tree branch,
or find something
useful to do.
l could do that.
l've got some rope up here.
But l do not think
you would accept my help,
since l am only waiting around
to kill you.
That does put a damper
on our relationship.
But l promise
l will not kill you until
you reach the top.
That's very comforting,
but l'm afraid
you'll just have to wait.
l hate waiting.
l could give you my word
as a Spaniard.
(GRUNTlNG) No good.
l've known too many Spaniards.
ls there any way
you'll trust me?
Nothing comes to mind.
l swear on the soul
of my father,
Domingo Montoya,
you will reach the top alive.
Throw me the rope.
Thank you.
We'll wait. . .wait. . .wait
until you're ready.
Again, thank you.
l do not mean to pry,
but you don't by any chance
happen to have six fingers
on your right hand?
Do you always begin
conversations this way?
My father was slaughtered
by a six-fingered man.
He was a great sword maker,
my father.
When the six-fingered man
appeared and requested
a special sword,
my father took the job.
He slaved a year
before he was done.
l've never seen its equal.
The six-fingered man
returned and demanded it,
but at one-tenth
his promised price.
My father refused.
Without a word,
the six-fingered man
slashed him through the heart.
l loved my father.
So, naturally, l challenged
his murderer to a duel.
l failed.
The six-fingered man
leave me alive.
But he gave me this.
How old were you?
l was 1 1 years old.
When l was strong enough,
l dedicated my life
to the study of fencing.
So, the next time we meet,
l will not fail.
l will go up
to the six-fingered man
and say,
"Hello. My name
is lnigo Montoya.
"You killed my father.
Prepare to die."
You've done nothing
but study swordplay?
More pursue it
than study, lately.
You see,
l cannot find him.
lt has been 20 years now.
l'm starting
to lose confidence.
l just work for Vizzini
to pay the bills.
There's not a lot of money
in revenge.
Well, l certainly hope
you find him someday.
You're ready then?
Whether l am or not,
you've been more than fair.
You seem a decent fellow.
l hate to kill you.
l hate to die.
Begin.
You are using
Bonetti's defense
against me, huh?
l thought it fitting,
considering
the rocky terrain.
Naturally,
you must expect me
to attack with Capo Ferro.
Naturally. But l find
that Thibault cancels out
Capo Ferro, don't you?
Unless the enemy
has studied his Agrippa.
Which l have!
You are wonderful.
Thank you.
l've worked hard
to become so.
l admit that you are
better than l am.
Then why are you smiling?
Because l know something
you don't know.
And what is that?
l am not left-handed.
(GRUNTlNG)
You are amazing.
l ought to be,
after 20 years.
(GRUNTlNG) There's something
l ought to tell you.
Tell me.
l'm not left-handed either.
Who are you?
No one of consequence.
l must know.
Get used to disappointment.
Okay.
(GRUNTlNG)
(PANTlNG)
Kill me quickly.
l would as soon destroy
a stained-glass window
as an artist like yourself.
However, since l can't have
you following me, either. . .
(GROANS)
Please understand, l hold you
in the highest respect.
lnconceivable!
Give her to me.
Catch up with us quickly.
What do l do?
Finish him.
Finish him your way!
Oh, good. My way.
Thank you, Vizzini.
Which one's my way?
Pick up one of those rocks.
Get behind the boulder.
ln a few minutes,
the man in black will come
running around the bend.
The minute
his head is in view,
hit it with the rock!
My way's not
very sportsmanlike.
l did that on purpose.
l didn't have to miss.
l believe you.
So what happens now?
We face each other
as God intended.
Sportsmanlike.
No tricks. No weapons.
Skill against skill alone.
You mean,
you'll put down your rock
and l'll put down my sword,
and we'll try
and kill each other
like civilized people?
l can kill you now.
Frankly, l think the odds
are slightly in your favor
at hand-fighting.
lt's not my fault
for being the biggest
and the strongest.
l don't even exercise.
(GRUNTlNG)
Look,
are you just fiddling around
with me, or what?
l just want you to feel
you're doing well.
l hate for people
to die embarrassed.
You're quick.
And a good thing, too.
Why are you wearing a mask?
Were you burned by acid
or something like that?
No, it's just that they're
terribly comfortable.
l think everyone will be
wearing them in the future.
(GRUNTlNG) l just figured why
you give me so much trouble.
(GROANlNG)
Why's that, do you think?
Well, l haven't fought
just one person for so long.
l've been specializing
in groups,
battling gangs
for local charities,
that kind of thing.
Why should that make
such a. . .difference?
Well, you see,
you use different moves
(GRUNTlNG)
when you're fighting
half a dozen people
than when you only have to be
worried about one.
l do not envy you the headache
you will have when you awake.
But in the meantime,
rest well and dream
of large women.
There was a mighty duel.
lt ranged all over.
They were both masters.
Who won? How did it end?
The loser ran off alone,
but the winner
followed those footprints
toward Guilder.
Shall we track them both?
The loser is nothing.
Only the Princess matters.
Clearly, this was all planned
by warriors of Guilder.
We must all be ready
for whatever lies ahead.
Could this be a trap?
l always think
everything could be a trap,
which is why l'm still alive.
So, it is down to you
and it is down to me.
lf you wish her dead,
by all means,
keep moving forward.
Let me explain.
There's nothing to explain.
You're trying to kidnap
what l've rightfully stolen.
Perhaps an arrangement
can be reached?
There will be no arrangement,
and you're killing her.
(GASPS)
Well, if there can be
no arrangement,
then we are at an impasse.
l'm afraid so. l can't compete
with you physically,
and you're no match
for my brains.
You're that smart?
Let me put it this way.
Have you ever heard of Plato,
Aristotle, Socrates?
Yes.
Morons.
Really?
ln that case, l challenge you
to a battle of wits.
For the Princess?
To the death?
l accept.
Good, then pour the wine.
lnhale this,
but do not touch.
l smell nothing.
What you do not smell is
called iocane powder.
lt is odorless, tasteless,
dissolves instantly in liquid,
and is among
the more deadly poisons
known to man.
Hmm.
(CHUCKLES)
All right.
Where is the poison?
The battle of wits
has begun.
lt ends when you decide,
and we both drink
and find out who is right
and who is dead.
But it's so simple.
All l have to do is divine
from what l know of you.
Are you the sort of man
who would put the poison
into his own goblet
or his enemy's?
Now, a clever man
would put the poison
into his own goblet
because he would know
that only a great fool would
reach for what he was given.
l'm not a great fool,
so l can clearly not choose
the wine in front of you.
But you must have known
l was not a great fool.
You would've counted on it,
so l can clearly not choose
the wine in front of me.
You've made your decision,
then?
Not remotely.
Because iocane
comes from Australia,
as everyone knows,
and Australia is entirely
peopled with criminals,
and criminals
are used to having people
not trust them,
as you are not trusted by me,
so l can clearly not choose
the wine in front of you.
Truly, you have
a dizzying intellect.
Wait till l get going.
Where was l?
Australia.
Yes. Australia.
And you must have suspected
l would have known
the powder's origin,
so l can clearly not choose
the wine in front of me.
You're just stalling now.
You'd like to think that,
wouldn't you?
You've beaten my giant,
which means you're
exceptionally strong,
so you could've put the poison
in your own goblet,
trusting on your strength
to save you,
so l can clearly not choose
the wine in front of you.
But you've also bested
my Spaniard, which means
you must've studied,
and in studying,
you must have learned
that man is mortal,
so you would've put the poison
as far from yourself
as possible,
so l can clearly not choose
the wine in front of me.
You're trying to trick me
into giving away something.
lt won't work.
lt has worked !
You've given everything away.
l know where the poison is.
Then make your choice.
l will, and l choose. . .
What in the world
can that be?
What? Where?
l don't see anything.
l could've sworn
l saw something.
No matter.
(CHUCKLlNG)
What's so funny?
l'll tell you in a minute.
First, let's drink,
me from my glass
and you from yours.
(CHUCKLlNG)
You guessed wrong.
You only think
l guessed wrong.
That's what's so funny.
l switched glasses
while your back was turned !
(LAUGHlNG) You fool,
you fell victim to one
of the classic blunders.
The most famous is
never get involved
in a land war in Asia,
but only slightly less
well known is this.
Never go in against a Sicilian
when death is on the line!
(LAUGHlNG)
Who are you?
l'm no one to be trifled with.
That is all
you ever need know.
To think, all that time
it was your cup
that was poisoned.
They were both poisoned.
l spent the last few years
building up an immunity
to iocane powder.
Someone has beaten a giant.
There will be great suffering
in Guilder if she dies.
Catch your breath.
lf you'll release me,
whatever you ask for ransom,
you'll get it, l promise you.
(LAUGHlNG)
And what is that worth,
the promise of a woman?
You're very funny, Highness.
l was giving you a chance.
lt does not matter
where you take me.
There's no greater hunter
than Prince Humperdinck.
He can track a falcon
on a cloudy day.
He can find you.
You think your dearest love
will save you?
l never said
he was my dearest love,
and yes, he will save me.
That l know.
You admit to me
you do not love your fiancé?
He knows l do not love him.
Are not capable of love,
is what you mean.
l have loved more deeply
than a killer like yourself
could ever dream.
That was a warning,
Highness.
The next time,
my hand flies on its own,
for where l come from,
there are penalties
when a woman lies.
locane. l'd bet my life on it.
And there are
the Princess's footprints.
She is alive, or was,
an hour ago.
lf she is otherwise
when l find her,
l shall be very put out.
Rest, Highness.
l know who you are.
Your cruelty
reveals everything.
You're the
Dread Pirate Roberts.
Admit it.
With pride.
What can l do for you?
You can die slowly,
cut into a thousand pieces.
(CLlCKlNG TONGUE)
Hardly complimentary,
Your Highness.
Why loose your venom on me?
You killed my love.
lt's possible.
l kill a lot of people.
Who was this love of yours?
Another prince like this one?
Ugly, rich and scabby?
No, a farm boy. Poor.
Poor and perfect.
With eyes like the sea
after a storm.
On the high seas
your ship attacked,
and the Dread Pirate Roberts
never takes prisoners.
l can't afford
to make exceptions.
l mean, once word leaks out
that a pirate has gone soft,
people begin to disobey you,
and then it's nothing
but work, work, work
all the time.
You mock my pain !
Life is pain, Highness.
Anyone who says differently
is selling something.
l remember this farm boy
of yours, l think.
This would be what?
Five years ago?
Does it bother you to hear?
Nothing you can say
will upset me.
He died well.
That should please you.
No bribe attempts
or blubbering.
He simply said,
"Please. Please,
l need to live."
lt was the "please"
that caught my memory.
l asked him what was
so important for him.
"True love," he replied.
And then he spoke of a girl
of surpassing beauty
and faithfulness.
l can only assume
he meant you.
You should bless me
for destroying him
before he found out
what you really are.
And what am l?
Faithfulness
he talked of, madam.
Your enduring faithfulness.
Now tell me truly.
When you found out
he was gone,
did you get engaged
to your prince
that same hour,
or did you wait a whole week
out of respect for the dead?
You mocked me once.
Never do it again !
l died that day!
(HORSES GALLOPlNG)
You can die, too,
for all l care!
(SHOUTlNG) As you wish !
Oh, my sweet Westley!
What have l done?
(GROANS)
(GROANlNG)
Disappeared.
He must have seen us
closing in.
Which might account
for his panicking into error.
Unless l am wrong,
and l am never wrong,
they are headed dead
into the Fire Swamp.
Can you move at all?
Move? You're alive.
lf you want, l can fly.
l told you l would always
come for you.
Why didn't you wait for me?
Well, you were dead.
Death cannot stop true love.
All it can do
is delay it for a while.
l will never doubt again.
There will never be a need.
GRANDSON: Oh, no, no, please.
What is it?
What's the matter?
They're kissing again.
Do we have to hear
the kissing part?
Someday, you may not
mind so much.
Skip on to the Fire Swamp.
That sounded good.
Oh.
You're sick.
l'll humor you.
So, now,
where were we here?
Oh, okay.
GRANDFATHER:
"Westley and Buttercup
raced along the ravine floor."
(HORSE NElGHlNG)
Ha! Your pig fiancé
is too late.
A few more steps
and we'll be safe
in the Fire Swamp.
We'll never survive.
Nonsense.
You're only saying that
because no one ever has.
(ANlMAL SQUEALlNG)
(GROWLlNG)
lt's not that bad.
l'm not saying
l'd like to build
a summer home here,
but the trees
are actually quite lovely.
(THUDDlNG)
(OMlNOUS POPPlNG)
(GASPS)
Well, now,
that was an adventure.
Singed a bit, were you?
You?
(OMlNOUS POPPlNG)
Well, one thing l will say,
the Fire Swamp certainly does
keep you on your toes.
This will all soon be
but a happy memory,
because Roberts' ship,
Revenge, is anchored
at the far end,
and l, as you know,
am Roberts.
But how is that possible,
since he's been
marauding 20 years
and you only left me
five years ago?
l, myself, am often surprised
at life's little quirks.
(OMlNOUS POPPlNG)
See, what l told you before
about saying
"please" was true.
lt intrigued Roberts,
as did my description
of your beauty.
Finally Roberts
decided something.
He said, "All right, Westley.
"l've never had a valet.
You can try it for tonight.
"l'll most likely kill you
in the morning."
Three years, he said that.
"Good night, Westley.
Good work.
"Sleep well.
l'll most likely kill you
in the morning."
lt was a fine time for me.
l was learning
to fence, to fight,
anything anyone
would teach me.
And Roberts and l
eventually became friends.
And then it happened.
What? Go on.
Roberts had grown so rich
he wanted to retire,
so he took me to his cabin
and told me a secret.
"l am not the Dread
Pirate Roberts," he said.
"My name is Ryan.
"l inherited the ship
from the previous
Dread Pirate Roberts,
"just as you
will inherit it from me.
"The man l inherited it from
was not the real
Dread Pirate Roberts either.
"His name was Cummerbund.
The real Roberts has been
retired 1 5 years
"and living like a king
in Patagonia." Thank you.
Then he explained the name
was the important thing
for inspiring
the necessary fear.
You see,
no one would surrender
to the Dread Pirate Westley.
So, we sailed ashore,
took on an entirely new crew,
and he stayed aboard
for a while, as first mate,
all the time
calling me Roberts.
Once the crew believed,
he left the ship,
and l have been Roberts
ever since.
Except, now
that we're together,
l shall retire
and hand the name over
to someone else.
ls everything clear to you?
(GASPlNG)
(SNlFFlNG)
(BOTH GASPlNG)
(COUGHlNG)
(ANlMAL SNARLlNG)
We'll never succeed.
We may as well die here.
No. No.
We have already succeeded.
l mean,
what are the three terrors
of the Fire Swamp?
One, the flame spurt.
No problem.
There's a popping sound
preceding each.
We can avoid that.
Two, the lightning sand,
but you were clever enough
to discover
what that looks like,
so in the future,
we can avoid that, too.
Westley, what about
the R.O. U.S.s?
Rodents of Unusual Size?
l don't think they exist.
(GROWLlNG)
(SNARLlNG)
(SCREAMlNG)
Westley!
(GROANlNG)
(OMlNOUS POPPlNG)
(ANlMAL SHRlEKlNG)
(SQUEALlNG)
We did it.
Now, was that so terrible?
(HORSE NElGHlNG)
Surrender.
You mean, you wish
to surrender to me?
Very well. l accept.
l give you
full marks for bravery.
Don't make yourself a fool.
But how will you capture us?
We know the secrets
of the Fire Swamp.
We can live there
quite happily for some time,
so whenever
you feel like dying,
feel free to visit.
HUMPERDlNCK:
l tell you once again,
surrender!
WESTLEY:
lt will not happen.
For the last time, surrender!
Death first!
Will you promise
not to hurt him?
What was that?
lf we surrender,
and l return with you,
will you promise
not to hurt this man?
May l live a thousand years
and never hunt again.
He is a sailor
on the pirate ship Revenge.
Promise to return him
to his ship.
l swear it will be done.
Once we are out of sight,
take him back to Florin
and throw him
in the Pit of Despair.
l swear it will be done.
l thought you were dead once,
and it almost destroyed me.
l could not bear it
if you died again,
not when l could save you.
Come, sir.
We must get you to your ship.
We are men of action.
Lies do not become us.
Well spoken, sir.
What is it?
You have six fingers
on your right hand.
Someone was looking for you.
Where am l?
(HOARSELY) The Pit of Despair.
Don't even think. . .
(CLEARlNG THROAT)
(NORMALLY) Don't even think
about trying to escape.
The chains are far too thick.
And don't dream
of being rescued either.
The only way in is secret.
Only the Prince,
the Count and l know
how to get in and out.
Then l'm here till l die?
Till they kill you, yeah.
Then why bother curing me?
The Prince and the Count
always insist
on everyone being healthy
before they're broken.
So, it's to be torture?
l can cope with torture.
You don't believe me?
You survived the Fire Swamp.
You must be very brave.
But nobody withstands
the machine.
She's been like that
ever since the Fire Swamp.
lt's my father's
failing health
that's upsetting her.
Of course.
GRANDFATHER: "The King died
that very night,
"and before
the following dawn,
"Buttercup and Humperdinck
were married.
"And at noon,
she met her subjects again,
this time as their queen."
My father's
final words were. . .
GRANDSON:
Hold it. Hold it, Grandpa.
You read that wrong.
She doesn't marry Humperdinck.
She marries Westley.
l'm just sure of it.
After all
that Westley did for her,
if she didn't marry him,
it wouldn't be fair.
Well, who says life is fair?
Where is that written?
Life isn't always fair.
l'm telling you,
you're messing up the story.
Now, get it right!
Do you want me
to go on with this?
Yes.
All right then.
No more interruptions.
"At noon,
she met her subjects again,
this time as their queen."
My father's final words were,
"Love her as l loved her,
"and there will be joy."
l present to you your queen,
Queen Buttercup.
(PEOPLE MUTTERlNG)
(BUGLES PLAYlNG)
WOMAN: Boo!
Boo!
Why do you do this?
Because you had love
in your hands
and you gave it up!
But they would've
killed Westley
if l hadn't done it.
Your true love lives,
and you marry another!
True love saved her
in the Fire Swamp
and she treated it
like garbage.
And that's what she is,
the queen of refuse!
So bow down to her
if you want, bow to her.
Bow to the queen of slime,
the queen of filth,
the queen of putrescence!
Boo! Boo!
Rubbish ! Filth ! Slime!
Muck! Boo! Boo!
Boo!
(GASPlNG)
GRANDFATHER: "It was 1 0 days
till the wedding.
"The King still lived,
but Buttercup's nightmares
were growing steadily worse."
GRANDSON: See?
Didn't I tell you she'd never
marry that rotten Humperdinck?
Yes, you're very smart.
Shut up.
lt comes to this.
l love Westley.
l always have.
l know now,
l always will.
lf you tell me
l must marry you in 1 0 days,
please believe
l will be dead by morning.
l could never cause you grief.
Consider our wedding off.
You, uh, returned
this Westley to his ship?
Yes.
Then we will
simply alert him.
Beloved,
are you certain
he still wants you?
After all, it was you
who did the leaving
in the Fire Swamp.
Not to mention that, uh,
pirates are not known
to be men of their words.
My Westley
will always come for me.
Uh. . .
l suggest a deal.
You write four copies
of a letter.
l'll send
my four fastest ships,
one in each direction.
The Dread Pirate Roberts
is always close to Florin
this time of year.
We'll run up the white flag
and deliver your message.
lf Westley wants you,
bless you both.
lf not,
please consider me
as an alternative
to suicide.
Are we agreed?
Your princess is really
quite a winning creature.
A trifle simple, perhaps,
but her appeal is undeniable.
l know. The people
are quite taken with her.
lt's odd,
but when l hired Vizzini
to have her murdered
on our engagement day,
l thought that was clever.
But it's going to be
so much more moving
when l strangle her
on our wedding night.
Once Guilder is blamed,
the nation will be
truly outraged.
They'll demand we go to war.
(CHUCKLlNG)
Now, where is that
secret knot?
lt's impossible to find.
Ah !
Are you coming down
into the pit?
Westley's got
his strength back.
l'm starting him
on the machine tonight.
Tyrone,
you know how much l love
watching you work.
But l've got my country's
500th anniversary to plan,
my wedding to arrange,
my wife to murder,
and Guilder to frame for it.
l'm swamped.
Get some rest.
lf you haven't got
your health,
you haven't got anything.
Beautiful, isn't it?
Took me half a lifetime
to invent it.
l'm sure you've discovered
my deep and abiding
interest in pain.
At present, l'm writing
the definitive work
on the subject.
So, l want you to be
totally honest with me
on how the machine
makes you feel.
This being our first try,
l'll use the lowest setting.
(GROANlNG)
(GRUNTlNG)
As you know, the concept
of the suction pump
is centuries old.
Really, that's all this is,
except that instead
of sucking water,
l'm sucking life.
l've just sucked
one year of your life away.
l might one day
go as high as five,
but l really don't know
what that would do to you.
So, let's just start
with what we have.
What did this do to you?
Tell me.
And remember,
this is for posterity,
so be honest.
How do you feel?
(WHlMPERlNG)
lnteresting.
(YELLlN CLEARS THROAT)
Yellin.
Sire.
As Chief Enforcer
of all Florin,
l trust you
with this secret.
Killers from Guilder
are infiltrating
the Thieves' Forest
and plan to murder my bride
on our wedding night.
My spy network has
heard no such news.
Any word from Westley?
Too soon, my angel.
Patience.
He will come for me.
Of course.
She will not be murdered !
On the day of the wedding,
l want the Thieves' Forest
emptied,
and every inhabitant arrested.
(SlGHlNG) Many of the thieves
will resist.
My regular enforcers
will be inadequate.
Form a Brute Squad, then !
l want the Thieves' Forest
emptied before l wed.
lt won't be easy, sire.
Try ruling the world sometime.
(PEOPLE CLAMORlNG)
GRANDFATHER: "The day
of the wedding arrived.
"The Brute Squad had
their hands full carrying out
Humperdinck's orders."
(NElGHlNG)
(MEN SHOUTlNG)
ls everybody out?
Almost.
There's a Spaniard
giving us some trouble.
Well, you give him
some trouble.
Move.
l am waiting for you, Vizzini.
You told me to go back
to the beginning, so l have.
This is where l am
and this is where l'll stay.
l will not be moved.
Ho, there!
l do not budge.
Keep your "Ho, there."
But the Prince gave orders.
(GRUNTlNG)
So did Vizzini.
When a job went wrong,
you went back
to the beginning.
Well, this is where
we got the job,
so it's the beginning.
And l am staying
till Vizzini comes.
You, Brute,
come here!
l am waiting
for Vizzini.
You surely are a meanie.
Hello.
lt's you.
True.
(GROANS)
You don't look so good.
(SPUTTERlNG)
You don't smell
so good either.
Perhaps not.
l feel fine.
(THUDDlNG)
GRANDFATHER: "Fezzik and Inigo
were reunited.
"And as Fezzik
nursed his inebriated friend
back to health,
"he told Inigo
of Vizzini's death
"and the existence
of Count Rugen,
"the six-fingered man.
"Considering Inigo's
life-long search,
"he handled the news
surprisingly well.
"Fezzik took great care
in reviving Inigo."
That's enough !
Where is this Rugen now,
so l may kill him?
He's with the Prince
in the castle.
But the castle gate
is guarded by 30 men.
(GRUNTlNG)
How many could you handle?
l don't think more than 1 0.
Leaving 20 for me.
At my best, l could
never defeat that many.
l need Vizzini to plan.
l have no gift for strategy.
But Vizzini is dead.
No. Not Vizzini.
l need the man in black.
What?
Look. He bested you
with strength, your greatness.
He bested me with steel.
He must have
outthought Vizzini.
And a man who can do that
can plan my castle onslaught
any day.
Let's go.
Where?
Find the man in black,
obviously.
But you don't know
where he is.
Don't bother me with trifles.
After 20 years,
at last my father's soul
will be at peace.
There will be blood tonight!
Rise and report.
YELLlN: The Thieves' Forest
is emptied.
Thirty men guard
the castle gate.
Double it.
My princess must be safe.
The gate has but one key.
And l carry that.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACHlNG)
Ah ! My dulcet darling.
Tonight, we marry.
Tomorrow morning,
your men will escort us
to Florin Channel,
where every ship in my armada
waits to accompany us
on our honeymoon.
Every ship
but your four fastest,
you mean.
Every ship
but the four you sent.
Yes. Yes, of course.
Naturally, not those four.
(CLEARlNG THROAT)
Your Majesty.
You never sent the ships.
Don't bother lying.
lt doesn't matter.
Westley will come
for me anyway.
You're a silly girl.
Yes, l am a silly girl,
for not having seen sooner
that you are nothing
but a coward
with a heart full of fear.
l would not say such things
if l were you.
Why not? You can't hurt me.
Westley and l are joined
by the bonds of love.
And you cannot track that,
not with
a thousand bloodhounds.
And you cannot break it,
not with a thousand swords.
And when l say
you're a coward,
that is only because
you are the slimiest weakling
ever to crawl the earth !
l would not say
such things if l were you !
You truly love each other,
and so you might have been
truly happy.
Not one couple in a century
has that chance,
no matter what
the storybooks say.
And so,
l think no man in a century
will suffer as greatly
as you will.
Not to 50!
(YELLlNG)
Fezzik. Fezzik, listen.
Do you hear?
That is the sound
of ultimate suffering.
My heart made that sound
when Rugen slaughtered
my father.
The man in black
makes it now.
The man in black?
His true love is marrying
another tonight,
so who else has the cause
for ultimate suffering?
Excuse me. Pardon me,
it's important.
Fezzik, please.
(SHOUTlNG) Everybody, move!
Thank you.
lNlGO:
Where is the man in black?
You get there
from this grove, yes?
Fezzik, jog his memory.
l'm sorry, lnigo.
l didn't meant to jog him
so hard.
lnigo?
Father, l have failed you
for 20 years.
Now, our misery can end.
Somewhere. . .
Somewhere close by
is a man who can help us.
l cannot find him alone.
l need you.
l need you to guide my sword.
Please.
Guide my sword.
He's dead.
Just is not fair.
Grandpa, Grandpa,
wait. Wait.
What did Fezzik mean,
"He's dead"?
l mean, he didn't mean "dead."
Westley's only faking, right?
You want me
to read this or not?
Who gets Humperdinck?
l don't understand.
Who kills Prince Humperdinck?
At the end?
Somebody's gotta do it.
ls it lnigo? Who?
Nobody. Nobody kills him.
He lives.
You mean, he wins?
Jesus, Grandpa,
what did you read me
this thing for?
You know,
you've been very sick
and you're taking this story
very seriously.
l think we ought to
stop now.
No, l'm okay. l'm okay.
Sit down. l'm all right.
Okay.
All right, now, let's see.
Where were we?
Oh, yes.
ln the Pit of Despair.
Well. . .
The Montoyas have
never taken defeat easily.
Come along, Fezzik.
Bring the body.
The body?
Have you any money?
l have a little.
l just hope it's enough
to buy a miracle, that's all.
MlRACLE MAX: Go away!
What? What?
Are you the Miracle Max
who worked for the King
all those years?
The King's
stinking son fired me,
and thank you so much
for bringing up
such a painful subject.
While you're at it,
why don't you give me
a nice paper cut
and pour lemon juice on it?
We're closed !
Beat it, or l'll call
the Brute Squad.
l'm on the Brute Squad.
You are the Brute Squad.
We need a miracle.
lt's very important.
Look, l'm retired.
And besides,
why would you want someone
the King's stinking son fired?
l might kill whoever
you wanted me to miracle.
He's already dead.
He is, huh? l'll take a look.
Bring him in.
l've seen worse.
Sir?
Huh?
We're in a terrible rush.
Don't rush me, sonny.
You rush a miracle man,
you get rotten miracles.
You got money?
Sixty-five.
(SCOFFlNG)
l never worked for so little,
except once, and that was
a very noble cause.
This is noble, sir.
His wife is crippled.
His children are
on the brink of starvation.
Are you a rotten liar.
l need him
to help avenge my father,
murdered these 20 years.
Your first story was better.
Where's that bellows cranny?
He probably
owes you money, huh?
Well, l'll ask him.
He's dead. He can't talk.
(SCATTlNG)
Look who knows so much, huh.
Well, it just so happens
that your friend here
is only mostly dead.
There's a big difference
between mostly dead
and all dead.
Please, open his mouth.
Now, mostly dead
is slightly alive.
Now, all dead. . .
Well, with all dead,
there's usually only one thing
that you can do.
What's that?
Go through his clothes
and look for loose change.
Hey!
Hello in there! Hey!
What's so important?
What you got here
that's worth living for?
True
love.
True love. You heard him.
You could not ask for
a more noble cause than that.
Sonny, true love is
the greatest thing
in the world,
except for a nice M. L.T.
A mutton, lettuce
and tomato sandwich
when the mutton
is nice and lean
and the tomato is ripe.
(SMACKlNG LlPS)
They're so perky. l love that.
But that's not what he said.
He distinctly said,
"To blave."
And as we all know,
"to blave" means "to bluff."
Huh?
So you're probably
playing cards
and he cheated. . .
Liar! Liar!
Liar!
Get back, witch !
l'm not a witch,
l'm your wife!
But after what
you just said,
l'm not even sure
l want to be that anymore.
You never had it so good.
"True love."
He said "true love," Max.
Don't say another word,
Valerie.
He's afraid. Ever since
Prince Humperdinck fired him,
his confidence is shattered.
Why'd you say that name?
You promised me that
you'd never say that name!
What, Humperdinck?
(SHOUTlNG)
Humperdinck! Humperdinck!
Humperdinck!
l'm not listening !
True love lies expiring,
(SHUDDERlNG)
and you don't have the decency
to say why you won't help.
Nobody's hearing nothing.
Humperdinck! Humperdinck!
lNlGO:
This is Buttercup's true love.
lf you heal him, he will
stop Humperdinck's wedding.
Humperdinck!
Wait, wait.
l make him better,
Humperdinck suffers?
Humiliations galore.
(LAUGHlNG)
(SCATTlNG)
That is a noble cause.
Give me the 65.
l'm on the job.
(EXCLAlMS)
That's a miracle pill?
The chocolate coating
makes it go down easier.
But you have to wait
1 5 minutes for full potency.
And you shouldn't go in
swimming after for at least. . .
What?
An hour. A good hour.
Yeah, an hour.
Thank you for everything.
Okay.
Bye-bye, boys.
Have fun
storming the castle.
Think it'll work?
lt would
take a miracle.
Bye-bye!
Bye!
(SHEEP BLEATlNG)
(GRUNTlNG)
lnigo, there's more than 30.
What's the difference?
We've got him. Help me here.
We'll have to
force-feed him.
Has it been 1 5 minutes?
We can't wait.
The wedding's
in half an hour.
We must strike in the hustle
and the bustle beforehand.
Tilt his head back.
Open his mouth.
How long do we have to wait
before if we know
if the miracle works?
Your guess is
as good as mine.
l'll beat you at your part.
l'll take you both together!
l guess not very long.
Why won't my arms move?
You've been
mostly dead all day.
We had Miracle Max
make a pill
to bring you back.
Who are you?
Are we enemies?
Why am l on this wall?
Where is Buttercup?
Let me explain.
No, there is too much.
Let me sum up.
Buttercup is marrying
Humperdinck in a little less
than half an hour,
so all we have to do is
get in, break up the wedding,
steal the princess,
make our escape.
After l kill Count Rugen.
That doesn't leave much time
for dilly-dallying.
You just wiggled your finger.
That's wonderful.
l've always been
a quick healer.
What are our liabilities?
There is but one
working castle gate.
Come on.
And it is guarded by 60 men.
And our assets?
Your brains,
Fezzik's strength,
my steel.
That's it? lmpossible.
lf l had a month to plan,
maybe l could come up
with something, but this. . .
You just shook your head.
That doesn't make you happy?
My brains, his steel
and your strength
against 60 men,
and you think a little
head jiggle is supposed
to make me happy? Hmm?
lf we only had a wheelbarrow,
that would be something.
Where did we put
the wheelbarrow
the albino had?
Over the albino, l think.
Why didn't you list that
among our assets
in the first place?
(SlGHlNG)
What l wouldn't give
for a holocaust cloak.
There, we cannot help you.
Will this do?
Where did you get that?
At Miracle Max's.
lt fit so nice,
he said l could keep it.
All right, all right.
Come on. Help me up.
Now, l'll need
a sword, eventually.
Why?
You can't even lift one.
True, but that's hardly
common knowledge, is it?
Thank you. Now,
there may be problems
once we're inside.
l'll say.
How do l find the Count?
Once l do,
how do l find you again?
Once l find you again,
how do we escape?
Don't pester him.
He's had a hard day.
Right. Right. Sorry.
lnigo.
What?
l hope we win.
HUMPERDlNCK:
You don't seem excited,
my little muffin.
Should l be?
Brides often are,
l'm told.
l do not marry tonight.
My Westley will save me.
(CRlCKETS CHlRPlNG)
(PEOPLE CHATTERlNG)
(ORGAN PLAYlNG)
(GARBLlNG) Marriage.
Marriage is what
brings us together
today.
Marriage,
that blessed arrangement,
that dream
within a dream.
YELLlN:
Stand your ground, men !
Stand your ground !
(PEOPLE MURMURlNG)
YELLlN: Stand your ground !
l am the Dread Pirate Roberts!
(MEN EXCLAlMlNG)
There will be no survivors!
Now?
Not yet.
My men are here, l am here,
but soon you will not be here.
Now!
Light him.
The Dread Pirate Roberts
takes no survivors.
All your worst nightmares
are about to come true!
Then love,
true love,
will follow you
forever.
The Dread Pirate Roberts
(HOARSELY)
is here for your souls!
(ALL CLAMORlNG)
YELLlN: Stay where you are!
Stand and fight.
Stay where you are!
So treasure your love. . .
Skip to the end.
Have you the ring?
(RUMBLlNG)
Here comes my Westley now.
Fezzik, the portcullis!
(GRUNTlNG)
Your Westley is dead.
l killed him myself.
Then why is there fear
behind your eyes?
Give us the gate key.
l have no gate key.
Fezzik, tear his arms off.
Oh, you mean this gate key.
And do you,
Princess Buttercup. . .
Man and wife!
Say, "Man and wife!"
Man and wife.
Escort the bride
to the honeymoon suite.
l'll be there shortly.
He didn't come.
Kill the dark one
and the giant,
but leave the third
for questioning.
(GRUNTlNG)
Hello.
My name is lnigo Montoya.
You killed my father.
Prepare to die.
Fezzik! l need you !
l can't leave him alone.
He's getting away from me,
Fezzik! Please!
Fezzik!
l'll be right back.
(GRUNTlNG)
Thank you.
Strange wedding.
Yes, a very strange wedding.
Come along.
What was that for?
Because you've always been
so kind to me.
And l won't be
seeing you again,
since l'm killing myself
once we reach
the honeymoon suite.
Won't that be nice?
She kissed me!
(LAUGHlNG)
(GROANS)
Sorry, Father.
l tried.
You must be
that little Spanish brat
l taught a lesson to
all those years ago.
Simply incredible.
Have you been chasing me
your whole life,
only to fail now?
l think that's the worst thing
l've ever heard.
How marvelous.
WESTLEY: There's a shortage
of perfect breasts
in this world.
lt would be a pity
to damage yours.
Westley!
Oh, Westley, darling !
Westley,
why won't you hold me?
Gently.
At a time like this?
That's all you can
think to say? "Gently"?
Gently!
(GRUNTS)
TYRONE: Good heavens.
Are you still trying to win?
You've got an overdeveloped
sense of vengeance.
lt's going to get you
into trouble someday.
Hello.
My name is lnigo Montoya.
You killed my father.
Prepare to die.
Hello.
My name is lnigo Montoya.
You killed my father.
Prepare to die.
Hello!
My name is lnigo Montoya.
You killed my father.
Prepare to die.
Stop saying that!
(GROANS)
Hello!
My name is lnigo Montoya!
You killed my father!
Prepare to die.
No!
Offer me money.
Yes.
Power, too.
Promise me that.
All that l have and more.
Please.
Offer me everything l ask for.
Anything you want.
(GROANS)
l want my father back,
you son of a bitch.
Westley,
will you ever forgive me?
What hideous sin
have you committed lately?
l got married.
l didn't want to.
lt all happened so fast.
lt never happened.
What?
But it did. l was there.
This old man said,
"Man and wife."
Did you say, "l do"?
No. We sort of
skipped that part.
Then you're not married.
lf you didn't say it,
you didn't do it.
Wouldn't you agree,
Your Highness?
A technicality that will
shortly be remedied.
But first things first.
To the death.
WESTLEY: No!
To the pain.
l don't think
l'm quite familiar
with that phrase.
l'll explain.
And l'll use small words,
so that you'll be sure
to understand,
you warthog-faced buffoon.
That may be
the first time in my life
a man has dared insult me.
lt won't be the last.
"To the pain" means
the first thing you lose
will be your feet,
below the ankles.
Then your hands at the wrists.
Next, your nose.
And then my tongue, l suppose?
l killed you too quickly
the last time,
a mistake l don't mean
to duplicate tonight.
l wasn't finished !
The next thing you lose
will be your left eye,
followed by your right.
And then my ears.
l understand.
Let's get on with it.
Wrong ! Your ears you keep,
and l'll tell you why.
So that every shriek
of every child at seeing
your hideousness
will be yours to cherish.
Every babe that weeps
at your approach,
every woman who cries out,
"Dear, God,
what is that thing?"
will echo
in your perfect ears.
That is what
"to the pain" means.
lt means l leave you
in anguish,
wallowing in freakish
misery forever.
l think you're bluffing.
lt's possible, pig.
l might be bluffing.
lt's conceivable,
you miserable, vomitous mass,
that l'm only lying here
because l lack the strength
to stand.
Then again,
perhaps l have
the strength after all.
Drop your sword.
(SWORD DROPS)
Have a seat.
Tie him up.
Make it as tight
as you like.
HUMPERDlNCK: Oh.
Where's Fezzik?
l thought
he was with you.
No.
ln that case. . .
Help him.
Why does Westley
need helping?
lNlGO: Because he has
no strength.
l knew it.
l knew you were bluffing !
l knew he was bluffing.
Shall l dispatch him
for you?
Thank you, but no.
Whatever happens to us,
l want him to live
a long life, alone
with his cowardice.
FEZZlK: lnigo!
lnigo, where are you?
Oh, there you are.
lnigo, l saw
the prince's stables.
And there they were.
Four white horses.
And l thought,
"There are four of us,
if we ever find the lady."
Hello, lady.
So l took them with me,
in case we ever bumped into
each other.
l guess we just did.
Fezzik, you did
something right.
Don't worry,
l won't let it go to my head.
You know,
it's very strange.
l have been in
the revenge business so long,
now that it's over,
l don't know what to do
with the rest of my life.
Have you ever
considered piracy?
You'd make a wonderful
Dread Pirate Roberts.
GRANDFATHER:
"They rode to freedom.
"And as dawn arose,
Westley and Buttercup knew
they were safe.
"A wave of love
swept over them,
"and as they reached
for each other..."
What? What?
No, it's kissing again.
You don't want to hear that.
l. . . l don't mind so much.
Okay.
"Since the invention
of the kiss, there have
been five kisses
"that were rated
the most passionate,
the most pure.
"This one left them
all behind.
"The end."
Now, l think
you ought to go to sleep.
Okay.
All right.
So long.
Grandpa?
Maybe you could come over
and read it again
to me tomorrow.
As you wish.
(STORYBOOK LOWE PLAYlNG)
Come my love
I'll tell you a tale
Of a boy and girl
and their love story
And how he loved her
Oh, so much
And all the charms
she did possess
Now this did happen
once upon a time
When things
were not so complex
And how he worshipped
the ground she walked
And when he looked
in her eyes
He became obsessed
My love is like
a storybook story
But it's as real
as the feelings I feel
My love is like
a storybook story
But it's as real
as the feelings I feel
It's as real
He said, "Don't you know
I love you, oh, so much
"And lay my heart
at the foot of your dress?"
She said, "Don't you know
that storybook loves
"Always have
a happy ending?"
Then he swooped her up
just like in the books
And on his stallion
they rode away
My love is like
a storybook story
But it's as real
as the feelings I feel
My love is like
a storybook story
But it's as real
as the feelings I feel
Best watched using Open Subtitles MKV Player